CS Akriti Chaturvedi

Phone: +91 8307974126/807752384 Email: csakriti93@gmail.com Location: Delhi, India LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/akriti-chaturvedi

Profile Summary:

A qualified **Company Secretary** and **Law Graduate** having **3+ years of experience** of managing **corporate governance** and **compliance function** in **India & across Asia Pacific countries**. Currently working with British telecom as part of their Corporate Governance Team for Asia Pacific region.

BT Group plc (trading as BT and formerly British Telecom) is a British multinational telecommunication having headquarter in London, United Kingdom. It has operations in around 180 countries and is the largest provider of fixed-line, broadband and mobile services in the UK, and also provides subscription television and IT services.

***** Key Work Areas:

- Conducting Board Meeting, Annual General Meeting, General Meeting, Extra Ordinary General Meeting of the Company.
- ➤ Drafting of Minutes, Notices, Agendas, Attendance sheet and other documents of Board as well as general meeting Preparation of Director's Written Resolution and passing in accordance with relevant laws.
- Superintending and drafting of notices, resolutions and maintenance of minutes of Board Meetings & General Meetings
- Assisting other professionals for conducting the Secretarial Audit of the Company under the provisions of Companies Act, 2013.
- Maintaining all statutory books & records of the company under Companies Act, 2013.
- Coordinating the production, publication and distribution of annual reports, interim / quarterly reports and announcements.
- Preparing, reviewing & formulation of resolutions and other documents and forms for Change of Registered office, Change of place of co-sec records, appointment of legal representative, appointment of Authorized signatories, appointment of HSBC Bank Signatories, Appointment / resignation of directors/ Company Secretary/ Auditors of the Company.
- Prepared various forms & documents related to Appointment, Reappointment & Resignation of Auditors & First Auditor in General Meetings.
- > Amendment of Articles of Association as per Hong Kong Companies Ordinance.
- > Assisted on Adoption & Alteration of Articles of Association & Memorandum of Association.
- Increase of Authorized Share Capital of Company.
- Worked on Dividend Distribution, Redemption of preference shares, Reduction of share capital & other methods of Capital Repatriation.
- Supervised of Transfer & Transmission of Shares, Share Split & issue of Duplicate Share Certificates.
- Compliances of Roll over of Preference Shares of Company.
- Engaged in Incorporation of Companies & LLP under SPICe.
- Strike off of Companies as well as Limited Liability Partnership.
- Handling Annual Filling of whole APAC region.
- Drafting of briefing paper for Directors, Comparative quotes based on different quotes provided by suppliers, review of documents, forms, passing of ordinary and special resolutions for the purpose Merger / Amalgamation / Liquidation of entities in different countries.
- > Drafting various Agreement, Resolutions, Affidavits, Memorandum of Understanding etc.
- > Preparation of presentation for Directors for providing them Financial & operational updates.
- Liaising / Negotiating with the Companies Key Suppliers such as Deloitte / PWC/ KPMG / BDO.
- Assisting Companies Auditor in for Quarterly/ half yearly and annual audits.
- R&D on Acts, rules, notifications of various countries for the Identification of Beneficial owners in respective countries.

- Instructing and co-ordinating with the Notary public of different countries for the purpose of notarization, legalization and apostilization of documents.
- Familiar with international legal authorities & their portal like DBD (Thailand)/ ACRA (Singapore)/ SEC (Philippines)/ ASIC (Australia) etc.
- Performed online inspection of ROC documents of various companies Prepared various forms & documents related to Appointment, Resignation and Re- Designation of Directors & Key.
- Convening of Meetings at Shorter Notice.
- Managerial Personnel in Board Meetings as well as General Meetings.
- Successfully updating of various E-Forms including DIR 12, INC-22A, ADT 1, ADT 3, MGT 14, AOC 4, MGT 7, DPT-3, MSME I etc.
- Independently handling Purchase order procedure which includes raising spend requests, approval of invoices & sharing them with Central Finance Team & Accounts payable team for payment.
- > Creating matters on ONIT & iManage.
- Closely Monitoring work performed by supplier.
- Assisting supplier on renewal on Telecom Licenses in Indonesia & Philippines.
- Regularly updating, managing, reviewing Blueprint and SharePoint.
- Draft, prepare, review and edit routine documents (including NDA's, SOWs) with low to medium complexity.
- ➤ Change of Designation on Email address & Mobile number as per the new requirement in Philippines.
- Communicating & liasoning with Banks, ROC, agents and other professional firms.

Work Experience:

Company Secretary	British Telecomm	Feb 2020 - Present
Company Secretary	s.Oliver Fashion (India) Pvt Ltd	June 2019 - Jan 2020
Company Secretary Trainee	Anna Infrastructures Limited	Jan 2018 - April 2019

Professional Qualification:

Company Secretary	ICSI	2018
LL.B	DBRAU	2017

Academic Qualification:

B.Com	DBRAU, Agra	2014
Intermediate	Holi Public School, Agra, CBSE	2011
High School	University Model School, Agra, CBSE	2009

IT Skills:

- MS Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)
- Fully conversant with MCA 21 application for E-Filling of documents and other records
- Completed Computer Training Course as per ICSI Requirement.
- Conversant with Computax & Cleartax Softwares
- Blueprint
- Sharepoint
- > ONIT